# PRAMOD KOTIPALLI

**☑** pramodk@gatech.edu

pramodk.net

**4** +1 (425) 200-5436

in pramodkotipalli

**(7)** p13i

# **SKILLS**

#### **LANGUAGES**

Python

Javascript/TypeScript

C#

Java

MATLAB

### **FRAMEWORKS**

Django + REST ASP.NET MVC + WebAPI Ionic Framework

#### WEB DEVELOPMENT

AngularJS Responsive HTML/CSS Razor/CSHTML

#### APPLICATION DEPLOYMENT

Heroku

Microsoft Azure

### **CONTINUOUS INTEGRATION**

Jenkins

Travis CI / CircleCI / Wercker

### **DATABASES**

PostgreSQL Redis

### VMS + CONTAINERS

Docker + Docker Compose Vagrant + VirtualBox

#### **APIS + LIBRARIES**

Django Channels KaTeX/MathJax scikit-learn Celery + RabbitMQ ELK

### **IDES + ENVIORNMENTS**

PyCharm IntelliJ IDEA Visual Studio + ReSharper

#### OTHER PROFICIENCIES

Git + Git Flow n-tier application architecture designing RESTful APIs LaTeX Shell Scripting

# **SUMMARY**

Results-oriented software engineer specializing in web application development. Worked on numerous personal and professional projects gaining significant professional experience in Python, Django, AngularJS, and Microsoft's ASP.NET C# framework. Also studying how machine learning and computer vision techniques can be applied to wearable sensors to predict future health outcomes.

# **EDUCATION**

Georgia Institute of Technology

Bachelors of Science Computer Science 2019

GPA: 3.89/4.00 (Faculty Honors)

Coursework: Machine Learning, Data Structures, Algorithms, Assembly & C, OOP

### **EXPERIENCE**

SpaceX · Software engineering intern

Hawthorne, CA · September 2017 to December 2017

- Future intern in Enterprise Information Systems group at SpaceX headquarters
- · Will develop software to empower industry-shaping rocket scientists and engineers

Cisco Systems · Software engineering intern

San Jose, CA · May 2017 to August 2017

- Developed tool to significantly reduce time to test Cisco's Cloud DVR services
- Driving development of RESTful APIs to abstract multi-host Docker container orchestration
- Led adoption of new technologies (e.g. task queues) and workflows (e.g. git feature-branch)
- Using: Docker, Django REST Framework, JMeter, Celery, RabbitMQ, ELK, Jenkins, Cisco UCS

# **PROJECTS**

RichCaptions: symbolic math captions for educational videos

September 2016

- · Identified and reconciled deficiency in viewing of educational videos on YouTube or Khan Academy.
- Recognizes that students learn better by seeing captions in math/science symbols instead of plain text.
- Designed/implemented UX for captioning and viewing videos with LaTeX-rendered math captions.
- Technologies used: AngularJS, KaTeX.js, Django REST Framework, YouTube API, PostgreSQL, Heroku.

MetroSync: a web app to help musicians rehearse together

June 2016

- Designed/implemented web app featuring metronome synced across devices aiding in musical practice.
- Allows a group leader to set tempo and time signature; plays synchronously on subscribed followers.
- Technologies used: Django Channels (web sockets), AngularJS.

# **AWARDS**

Grace Hopper conference travel grant · Google

October 2016

One of 100 students awarded full scholarship to attend Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing. Developed skills based on demonstrated interest/experience in promoting the role of women in computing.

Grand Prize winner · HackATL: startup-oriented hackathon at Emory University November 2016 Awarded for developing and presenting a comprehensive business plan to venture Atlanta-area VCs. Developed technology for on-demand community help in emergency situations on college campuses.

Faculty Honors · Office of the Registrar, Georgia Institute of Technology Awarded to full-time students who earn a 4.00 GPA in an academic term. Earned in Spring 2016, Summer 2016, and Spring 2017 terms.

2016

### **ACTIVITIES**

<gt-webdev/> · Marketing lead, officer, speaker

January 2016 to Present

Georgia Tech Leading Edge leadership development program ·

January 2016 to May 2016